Neil V. Rosenberg bluegrass music collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Sound recordings, Digital files are located in afc2002009_dc001. Please see the AFC reference staff for access.
  - Indian Springs Bluegrass Festival and other recordings, 1972-1975, AFC 2002/009: SR293; Carl Fleischhauer; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 01:35:40, Side 2: 01:35:50): analog, 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in.
    - Side 2
      - Miscellaneous Bob and Ray skits, 1973
        Dubbed from the LP Vintage Bob and Ray (Genesis 1047). The LP was released in 1973; the recordings date from the 1950s.
        - Wally Ballou visits glass fruit factory, undated
        - Dean Archer Armstead's Agricultural Forum of the Air, undated
        - Mister Science, undated
        - Aunt Penny's Sunlit Kitchen, undated
        - Grit commercial, 1951
  - Osborne Brothers at the American Legion Park, Culpeper, Virginia, August 20, 1967, AFC 2002/009: SR294; Bob Osborne; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:44, Side 2: 00:32:03): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Two shows and a jam session. From Bob Osborne, with his handwritten table of contents and note.
    - Side 1
      First show: Osborne Brothers, Dale Slead, and Ronnie Blackwell. Others on this show included Ralph Stanley, Don Reno, Harrell [sic], etc.
      - "I'll Be Alright Tomorrow"
      - "Me And My Old Banjo"
      - "Blue Moon Of Kentucky"
      - "Memories"
      - "Bugle Call Rag"
      - "This Heart Of Mine"
      - "Billy In The Lowground"
      - "The Kind Of Woman I Got"
      - "Up This Hill And Down"
      - "Making Plans"
      - "Roll Muddy River"
      - "Ruby"
    - Side 2
      Second show: same personnel, date, and location
      - "In The Pines"
      - "Lonesome Feeling"
      - "Sure-Fire"
      - "Walking The Floor Over You"
      - "Hard Times"
      - "Hey Hey Bartender"
      - "Steal Away"
      - "Lonesome Road Blues"
    - Jam session
      - "True Life Blues" - singing - Ralph, Bob
      - "I'll Fly Away" - everybody
      - "White Dove"
  - "Muleskinner" outtakes (undated); "Old and In The Way" live stuff (circa 1973) - both undated jam, Ewing, SR, with Pat Cloud; Alan Munde recorded by Steve Pottier, March 4, 1976, AFC 2002/009: SR295; Sandy Rothman (typewritten letter-cum-table of contents by SR); RXI 0175; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 01:35:51, Side 2: 01:34:49): analog, 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in.
  - Concert broadcast on WHFS (radio), Bethesda, MD, 1976, AFC 2002/009: SR296; The recording was given to Neil V. Rosenberg, possibly by Cheryl Brauner (a folklore graduate student), or Ali Kahn (her roommate).; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Track 1: 01:05:24, Track 2: 00:00:28, Track 3: 00:00:14, Track 4: 01:00:18): analog, 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in.
    One page handwritten table of contents by Neil V. Rosenberg.
    - Emmylou Harris and the Hot Band
    - Earl Scruggs Revue
  - "Molly and Tenbrooks" and "White House Blues", AFC 2002/009: SR297; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:09, Side 2: 00:31:07): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Accompanied by a six-page computer printout with Neil V. Rosenberg's transcription of two Stanleys songs on the recordings: "Molly and Tenbrooks" and "White House Blues"
    - Radio broadcast recording dubs, August 30, 1984, Gary Reid
      Photocopy of typewritten table of contents 1 p., with Neil V. Rosenberg's pencil annotations
    - Flatt and Scruggs, Stanley Brothers; WCYB Bristol VA, late 1947-early 1948
  - Dubs of sound disc recordings, AFC 2002/009: SR298
    - Sound recording, RXI 0176; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:47:17, Side 2: 00:28:52): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in.
      - Neil V. Rosenberg KRE 78 rpm acetates, December 13, 1955, February 27, 1956
      - Neil V. Rosenberg/LMS Toledo 33 1/3 acetates (November 1957), November 1957
      - JNR's two favorite Mills Brothers 78s
    - Documentation
      - Song list and production notes for SR038, April 21 and 25, 2011, April 25, 2011, nvr1955-12-13.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Barry Olivier's "Midnight Special" program on KPFA, circa late 1950s, AFC 2002/009: SR299
    - Sound recording, RYP 7400; 1 sound cassette: analog
      - "Black Girl" - Neil Rosenberg
      - "Blues" - Rolf Cahn and (possibly) Carl Granich
        Rolf, vocal and first guitar; Carl, second guitar (playing with a flat pick on a steel-string guitar)
    - Documentation
      - Song list and production notes for SR299, February 25, 2012, NVR Number 299 KPFA late 1950s.docx; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Digital surrogates of selected recordings in Series 3, afc2002009_dc001
    - Digitized sound recordings, 786 sound files: digital (.aif, .mp3, .wav)
      Audio files digitized by Brian Miksis from selected tapes. Includes high-resolution (aif or wav), medium-resolution CD pre-tagged (aif), and low-resolution pre-tagged (mp3) versions. Files form part of Miksis's "Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive" digitization project.
      Files are located at the dc001 filepaths listed under "Documentation" throughout Series 3.
    - Documentation of sound recordings and digitization, 19 manuscript: digital (.docx, .pdf, .txt)
      Additional documentation files, including documents explaining the digitization work of Miksis' "Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive" project and his chronological index to recordings.
      The introduction and chronological index are located in the top data folder of dc001; other documentation files are located at the dc001 filepaths listed under "Documentation" throughout Series 3.